<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Landing Page on GTL Python</title>
    <link>https://gtlpython.click/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Landing Page on GTL Python</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://gtlpython.click/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minesweeper</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/minesweeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 19:19:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/minesweeper/</guid>
      <description>Humble Beginnings Windows XP is before even my time&amp;hellip; Minesweeper is a puzzle game that came out around the 1990s as a game for personal computers. If you are not familiar with the game I invite you to Google &amp;lsquo;minesweeper&amp;rsquo; and play Google&amp;rsquo;s version of the game.
Implementing Minesweeper Your goal for this class will be to implement many of the functions required for a game of minesweeper. After you have these functions, you can then go and make your own version of the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Your Instructor</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello world, my name is JD Hagood, and I will be your instructor for this introduction to python class! I am looking forward to meeting everyone and teaching my favorite programming language!
Where am I from? I grew up in Clinton, Mississippi, USA with my parents and older sister. I attended a local highschool until my junior year and transferred to a public math and science magnet boarding school in the northern part of the state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Processing</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/audioprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/audioprocessing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this lab we will perform manipulations on audio files to produce some cool effects. Before we can start let&amp;rsquo;s talk about how sound is stored on a computer.
When you use a microphone to record a sound, it measures the electrical signal from a transducer which is proportial to the pressure at the transducer many times a second. This produces a list of numbers, called samples (both positive, zero, and negative), corresponding to the pressue at a certain time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/binarysearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/binarysearch/</guid>
      <description>Conditionals Let&amp;rsquo;s review conditionals from the pset.
The if statement in python has a simple syntax structure.
if CONDITION: CODE_TO_RUN_IF_CONDITION_IS_TRUE CODE_AFTER_IF_STATEMENT CONDITION is a boolean expression. A boolean expression is a piece of code that returns True or False when it is executed. Below are a couple of boolean expressions with numbers.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 3 == 3 True &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 3 == 4 False &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 3 &amp;lt; 4 True &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 3 &amp;gt; 4 False For a and b numbers, Python gives us these Boolean operators to make Boolean expressions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellular Atomata</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/cellular_atomata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/cellular_atomata/</guid>
      <description>For loops with range For loops are very versitile. In their most basic use case, they allow you to repeat a block of code mutliple times. We have seen them in this course before but it is worth going over them again.
Suppose you wanted to &amp;ldquo;hello&amp;rdquo; to the terminal 5 times. You could naively run the python script
print(&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;) print(&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;) print(&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;) print(&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;) print(&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;) However, any time you see idential blocks of code one after another alarm bells should go off in your head screaming &amp;lsquo;use a for loop!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DFS</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/dfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/dfs/</guid>
      <description>Sets If you have have so much as dipped your toes in higher level math, you have likely heard about sets. All of modern math is built on top of sets. In math a set is an unordered collection of objects. Sets can be constructed to hold almost anything anything from numbers to functions to cats and dogs to other sets (Russel has entered the chat).
In python we can create a set using curly braces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enviroment Model</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/environment_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/environment_model/</guid>
      <description>The Environment Diagram When you are programming in any language, it is important to have a mental model of what you are doing. If you are blindly executing code and run into a bug, it can be nearly impossible to figure out how to fix it on your own if you are not aware of what exactly you are writing. Environment diagrams help demystify many confusing aspects of Python and shine light on why many of the things in Python are done the way they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esp32 AP</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/esp32ap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/esp32ap/</guid>
      <description>A simple example program to set up an ESP32 as an Access Point to server a webpage to control an LED on an local wireless network.
import network # Import the network module to set up Wi-Fi import socket # Import the socket module for handling HTTP requests import machine # Import the machine module for controlling hardware led = machine.Pin(14, machine.Pin.OUT) # Create a Pin object for the LED, set as output # Configure the ESP32 as an Access Point (AP) ssid = &amp;#34;ESP32-AP&amp;#34; # Wi-Fi network name (SSID); Change this to something unique password = &amp;#34;12345678&amp;#34; # Password for the Wi-Fi network (must be at least 8 characters); Change this to something unique # Create an Access Point instance ap = network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generators</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/generators/</guid>
      <description>Reimplementing range Suppose we wanted to reimplement python&amp;rsquo;s range function. To do so we may naïvely implement a function that retuns a list of numbers in our desired range like this:
def list_range(start, stop, step=1): assert step &amp;gt;= 1 out = [] current = start while current &amp;lt; stop: out.append(current) current += step return out However, let&amp;rsquo;s try to use this function in the following program.
for i in list_range(0, 1_000_000_000_000_000, 1): if i &amp;gt; 100: break print(i) You will eventually see the numbers 0-99 printed on the screen, but not after a considerable pause!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hangman</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/hangman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/hangman/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s implement a simple game of hangman. If you are not familiar with this game, it is a word guessing game. A starting word is chosen, generally by another person, but in our case from a random list. You always know how many letters are in this word and you take turns guessing letters in the word. If the letter you guessed is in the word, then the letter position(s) in the word are revealed to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello, world</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Translation Everything on this website is written in English, which may make learning Python harder than it has to be. If you would rather not read English and are using Google Chrome, I recommend the extension &amp;ldquo;Immersive Translate&amp;rdquo; that will translate webpages for you. Once you install the extension, you can configure the settings to translate from English to Italian The translated webpage Downloading Python Before we can jump into programming, everyone needs to download Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursion</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/recursion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/recursion/</guid>
      <description>Recursion is one of the most useful tools that a programmer can have in their toolbelt. It can lead to very elegant solutions to problems that seem large or complicated at first by breaking it down into smaller pieces that can be more easily computed. Once you get the hang of it, you will also likely agree that the recursive programs are easier to understand. Let&amp;rsquo;s learn how to harness this power in python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sketchpad</title>
      <link>https://gtlpython.click/sketchpad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtlpython.click/sketchpad/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is JD, and I will be your instructor for this introduction to python class! I am looking forward to meeting everyone and teaching my favorite programming language: python.
Where am I from? I grew up in Clinton, Mississippi USA.
Download here: Download the ZIP file $$\int^\infty_0 e^{-x^2}dx = \frac{\sqrt{\pi}}{2}$$ The formula for the Gaussian integral is \( \int^\infty_0 e^{-x^2}dx = \frac{\sqrt{\pi}}{2} \). $$ \begin{array}{|c|c|c|} \hline \text{Header 1} &amp; \text{Header 2} &amp; \text{Header 3} \\ \hline \text{Data 1} &amp; \text{Data 2} &amp; \text{Data 3} \\ \text{Data 4} &amp; \text{Data 5} &amp; \text{Data 6} \\ \hline \end{array} $$ print(&amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34;) for i in range(10): print(f&amp;#34;num = {i}&amp;#34;) Change of config file detected, rebuilding site (#35).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
